scalemarket.com 2018-12-22

# ScaleMarket | Privacy Policy

A. Our privacy policy sets out how Scalemarket Corp.  uses and protects information that you give when you use our Scalemarket.com web.

B. We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected at all times. Any information that you provide will be handled in accordance with this privacy policy.

C. We may change this policy from time to time by updating this page and so you should check it regularly to ensure that you are happy with any changes.

D. Data we collect about you

We may collect the following information about you:

  1\.  Your Name

  2\. Company Name

  3\. Telephone Number

  4\. Email Address

  5\.  Any postal addresses that you provide

This information will be taken from you at the time that you make contact with us through the contact us page on our website or by email/telephone.

E. How we handle your data

We use this information for the following reasons:

1.        Process any orders you make through our platform and providing our service

2.       Improve our products and services

3.       For marketing our products and services to you

4.       For market research

F. We are committed to ensuring that the data you provide is handled securely and have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial processes to safeguard your information.

G. Cookies

Cookies are small files which are placed on your computer's hard drive. Cookies help this website to analyse traffic and visitors and help our site respond to you as an individual. We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used on our site and analyse visitor behaviour through statistics.

H. Links to other websites

You may encounter a link to an external website page whilst visiting our online store or profile on this website. If the link is to a website that is operated by a third party you should know that we have no control over that website and as such cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of your data or information you provide whilst visiting the site.

I. Controlling your information

You may request details of personal information that we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please contact us. If you believe that any information we hold about you is incorrect or incomplete then please write to or email us as soon as possible and we will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

J. Other data we hold and store

If you purchase a website from us we will store more information that you provide other than that listed in term 4 above. Please refer to the platform privacy policy, available in your ShopWired account, should you have any concerns about how we handle this data.

K. Sharing your data

We do not share your data with any third parties whatsoever.

## **1\. WHY ARE THE SCALES AND BALANCES SO IMPORTANT?**

The **[scales](http://www.scalemarket.com/scales-c1/), balances and load cells** are essential for ensuring the accuracy of measurements, especially for companies working in production and industrial areas. However, **[scales](http://www.scalemarket.com/scales-c1/) and balances** are used in many other industries, but also by householders and individuals. The scales and balances are used to measure the mass _**weigh or weight**_ in consumption of water, electrical energy, but also for measuring the **weigh** of physical objects. In order to keep the same units all over the world, so confusions wonâ€™t be made, international measurements were introduced, and the **scales and balances** made today must keep count of those matters. 

##  **2\. WHO CREATE THE WEIGHING INTERNATIONAL STANDARDS?**

The international standards for **[scales](http://www.scalemarket.com/scales-c1/), balances and load cell** are made by organizations such _OIML, NTEP, NIST and ASTM.._ Those standards must be made in the area of **weigh** and __mass measuring instruments__ , but also for control devices for _mass, weigh, water, gas, electricity and heat_. Once those standards are imposed, the companies producing such instruments must comply with those, and only the best companies are able to do so. It is a pity that so many consumers and buyers of scales, balances and load cell donâ€™t actually check if they buy approved and tested **precision weighing balance and[scales](http://www.scalemarket.com/scales-c1/) devices**, and this could lead to disastrous effects on the long term. 

## **3.WHAT IS PRODUCT PREPACKING AND WHY SCALES AND BALANCES ARE SO IMPORTANT FOR THIS?**

Product pre-packing represents the process of **weighing** , wrapping and packing materials before those are labeled. The **weight** content of packages must be measured, in order to determine the quantity of product inside in pounds (lb), kilograms (kg), grams (gr), Ounces (oz) etc. Here, _the[scales](http://www.scalemarket.com/scales-c1/) market metrology_ has an important role. This science allows the producers and authorities to verify the dimensions and **weight** of all the pre-packed products, and to verify the dimensions of those products using **_precise scales and balances in the market_**. For example, detergents, food for pets, ice cream, pharmaceutical products, textile products, beverage __market industry__ , concrete and cement, jewelry like gold, silver, diamonds, animal and cattle farm _market production_ , steel production, chemical products, pharmacy **scales** , **load cell manufacturing** , retail industry like super _markets_ , medical applications, frozen aliments, transportation and any other retail product must be verified. 

The **[scales](http://www.scalemarket.com/scales-c1/), balances and load cell** are important especially in __Europe and United States of America__ , where alcohol and wine is the subject of regulations and special taxes. The quantities must be verified precisely, so the authorities could establish what taxes should be paid by the producers of those **market products and services**. 

## **4\. MODULAR SCALE AND BALANCES FROM SCALE MARKET**

The modular **weights** measurements elements are at the base of automated testing systems. With the help of modular instruments, the engineers can choose a large variety of measuring instruments and data. Moreover, the _weighted dimensions_ must be ready to be transferred in computer programs, where they can be used for multiple purposes. 

As the respective instruments are modular and defined with the program, they can be changed at any time and redefined whenever the user needs those. This is why modular **[scale](http://www.scalemarket.com/scales-c1/), balances and load cell** respond to the dynamic and testing needs of clients. The virtual measuring instruments can be used for high-speed test, in a virtual environment that depends only of the limits of the computers technology. 

The oscilloscopes are used in high **precision[scale](http://www.scalemarket.com/scales-c1/), balances and load cell** with a high resolution and precision, which can be modified to meet the demands of clients. Besides those, there are also the signal generators that must be measured from many points of view. As the owner of a production company, you will have to make sure that you are using high precision instruments that would allow you to avoid severe mistakes. 

## **5\. WHICH SCALE AND BALANCES BRANDS DO SCALEMARKET BUY AND SALE?**

**Scalemarket** as an __international__ wholesale dealer, have many major **[scales](http://www.scalemarket.com/scales-c1/) balances and load cells** brands available for immediately delivery, as BuyCardinal scales, Detecto scales, Buy AND weighing balances, Ohaus balance, Buy Sartorius analytical and precision balances, Buy Fairbanks scales, Accuweigh scale, Buy Mettler Toledo weighing products, GSE scales, weightronix Agroindustrial weighing products, Buy Sentronik crane scale, Buy Adam floor scales, Buy Chatillon scales, Cas scale, Buy Dillon Dynamometers, Ametek, Buy Health O meter, Rice Lake, Buy Weighing Systems scales and balances, Seca medical scale, Buy Salter brecknell scale, Torbal pharmacy balances and Torrey price computing scale. 

By its great variety and high quality in every product, **ScaleMarket** is considered the "Universe of the **[scale](http://www.scalemarket.com/scales-c1/), Balances and Load Cells**". On this site you will find a host of products with attractive features, where you can serve is to choose which satisfaction will give you, always adjusted to suit your need when _weighing_. On our site, you also will have great professionals of long experience in the world of different _**weighing systems**_ , so that you feel the confidence to make the best decision when **buying **load cells** , scale or balances, either to build a complex weighing system for the simplest**. We have extensive catalog of products, which are distinguished by the quality hallmark of **Scalemarket** , which insurance will contribute in business or commercial development which, as every entrepreneur, you are looking for. Our _weighing systems_ aim to simplify your day to day activities, providing precision at every reading of quantity. All our products are tested previously, with the firm intention to ensure all our users a high-quality product, thus diminishing the faults, which supplies optimization in your valuable time. Do not wait any more, if you do not find the solution, we came up with it! 

**Call for quotes** , advice and general information with reference to any of our products, COMPLETELY FREE! You can also have contact in a way Online with any of our professionals for advice details via Skype. Contact us e-mail: contact@scalemarket.com; or telephone through the numbers: +1-305-403 2302
